好的  查莉  我们现在在宾馆  只是我们并不是在度假
Well, Charlie, here we are in our hotel room, and we're not on vacation.
想不通吗  放轻松吧  原因很不寻常
Confused? Well, get comfortable, because it's a doozy.
查莉  快从洗手间里出来
Charlie, get out of the bathroom!
就快了
In a minute!
嘿  拜托啦  各位
Hey. Come on, guys. Huh?
也没有很糟糕啦  算是一种历险吧
Not so bad. Kind of an adventure.
-拜托  省省吧  -安静点  闭嘴吧
- Oh, save it.  - Be quiet! Shut up.
拜托  我只是想尽力做到最好
Come on. I'm just trying to make the best of it.
-因为事情由你而起  -也不全是我的错
- Because you caused it. - Not totally my fault.
-那还能是谁的问题  -我想想再回答你
- Then whose fault was it? - I'll get back to you on that.
啊  泰迪  帮我一下
Ugh. Teddy, I need a hand.
至于我们是怎么落魄至此  那就说来话长了
So how we got here is kind of a long story.
我们暂且说今天是邓肯家族史上最黑暗的一天吧
Let's just say this is the worst day in Duncan family history.
-泰迪  快来  -来啦
- Teddy, now! - I'm coming!
未完待续
To be continued.
一周前
哦  听到了吗  托比
Oh. You hear that, Toby?
这叫做安静
It's called quiet.
安静在这房子里转瞬即逝  趁它还在时好好享受吧
Enjoy it while you can, because in this house it doesn't last long.
-妈妈  -嗯  告诉过你吧
- Mom! - Hmm? Told you.
托比的摇篮为什么在我房间里
Why is Toby's crib in my room?
因为你们俩要睡一个房间了
Because you two are sharing a room now.
-我们说好了的  -我们没有啊
- We talked about this. - No, we didn't.
没有吗  哦  反正我和托比说过了  他没意见
We didn't? Oh, well, Toby and I talked, and he's fine with it.
我不能和婴儿共住一个房间
I... I can't share a room with a baby.
我是个青少年了  我需要私人空间
I'm a teenager now. I need my own space.
好吧  孩子我很抱歉  但我们只有这么多房间
Well, I'm sorry, honey, but we only have so many rooms.
再说了  你很爱托比啊
Besides, you love Toby.
这不是爱不爱的问题  这事关房屋面积
This isn't about love. This is about square footage.
好吧  如果这么说能让你好受点的话
Well, if it makes it any easier,
你住进PJ房间时的年龄和托比现在差不多
Toby's about the same age you were when you moved in with P.J.
是啊  不过和PJ在一起时  是弟弟我掌大权
Yeah, but with me and P.J., the little brother was in charge.
这不适用于我们
That ain't happening with us.
哦  你太可爱了
Oh... aren't you adorable?
停下来  盖比  坚定信念
Stop that, Gabe! Stay strong.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast </i>
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
■
翻译： 不远景  Tracy  寂_翼  Juliet  Crazy王  Focus
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
■
校订： 苏赛崽  Enpistu
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
■
后期： Enpistu  liloelva
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好将来
<i>But I know your future's bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There's no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Sure life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love</i> <i>who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第三季第二十一集（本季完）
Good Luck Charlie  S03E21  All Fall Down
哦  PJ  你厨艺不错
Oh, hey, P.J. you are a good cook.
能尝一下这个怎么样吗
Could you taste this and tell me what you think?
好啊
Sure.
呃
Um...
这是什么
What is it?
啊  这问题真没水平
Well, that's not a good question.
这是新英格兰蛤蜊浓汤
It's New England clam chowder.
啊  那个  我没尝出浓汤味
Ah. Well, I'm not getting any chowder...
也没有蛤蜊
Or clams.
甚至不英格兰
Or even England.
不过  新倒是新的
It is new, though.
拜托啊
Oh man!
我只是想为斯宾塞做一顿特别的欢迎回家午餐
I wanted to make Spencer a special welcome-home lunch.
他去访问比帕了
He was visiting BIPA.
比帕  波士顿表演艺术学院的缩写
BIPA, the Boston Institute of Performing Arts.
他明年秋天想去那里就读
He's hoping to go there next Fall.
他已经到了  嘿  你能改良一下这个吗
There he is. Hey, um, do you think you could rescue this?
-没问题  -谢谢
- No problem. - Thank you.
第一步
Step one.
哦  太好啦  你回来了
Oh! I'm so glad you're home.
-在比帕怎么样  -超级好哇
- So how was BIPA? - Supa.
在波士顿他们是这么说"超级好"的
It's how they say "super" in Boston.
我知道的  嘿  你想知道他们怎么说
I know. Hey, you wanna hear how they say,
"去把车停到哈佛大学停车场"的吗
"go park your car in Harvard Yard"?
去把车哇停到哈佛大学停车场哇
"Pahk your cah in hahvahd yahd".
超级好哇
Supa.
我的更好笑
Mine's better.
所以呢  怎么样
So hey, how was it?
天哪  那所学校太好了
Oh my gosh, the school is amazing.
-真的  我爱上那里了  -那很好啊
- I mean, I loved it. - That's awesome.
那你什么时候能知道录取结果呢
So when do you find out if you got in?
我已经知道了
I already found out.
我被录取了
They accepted me.
很好啊  甜心
Way to go, boyfriend!
哦太好了
<i>Oh yeah, uh-huh.</i>
为什么只有我在跳开心舞
Why am I the only one doing a happy dance?
那是因为还有一件事情
Well, because... because there's one other thing.
嗯  他们想让我早入学一点
Um, they want me to start a little early.
要有多早
Well, like how early?
星期一
Monday.
-什么  -没错  这叫提前入学
- What?  - Yeah, it's called early enrollment.
他们现在有一个空的学位  如果我想去上学  就必须尽快
They have a space available and if I want it, I have to take it right now.
但你还没念完高中啊
But you haven't finished high school.
是这样的  不过我的学分已经足够毕业了
Yeah, I know, but I already have enough credits to graduate.
哇
Wow.
那真是
This is...
哇哦
Wow.
嘿  泰迪
Hey, Teddy...
我还没最后决定呢  我是说  我想先和你谈谈
I haven't made my decision yet. I mean, I wanted to talk to you first.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我不知道啊  我只是觉得有点突然
I don't know. I'm just kind of in shock.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
谁想来点芬香飘溢的新英格兰杂脍鸡肉面
Who's ready for some delicious New England chicken noodle chowder?
西式蛋饼呢
Denver Omelet?
各位  今天的工作真是难以置信啊
Guys, guys, I had an unbelievable day at work.
我来讲讲发生了什么吧
Wait until I tell you what happened.
哦  我好像听见托比在哭了
Oh, I think I hear Toby.
他就在那
Baby's right there.
-哦  那我就是听到查莉了  -查莉出去玩了
- Oh, then I think I hear Charlie. - Charlie's at a play date.
我就是不想听这个关于虫子的故事  帮帮我
I'm trying to get out of a bug story, work with me here.
好啦  我本来在安德逊家做一个日常的喷药工作
Okay. So I'm doing a routine spray job over at the Andersons'...
他们买了包月维护套装
They have a monthly maintenance package,
所以我每周二都去那
so that means I go every other Tuesday.
第一次是周边  第二次是里面
So the first Tuesday is perimeter, the second Tuesday's interior.
-我好像听到门铃在响  -才没呢
- I think I hear the doorbell. - Oh no, you don't.
总之  长话短说
Anyway, long story short...
-我抓到了这些小坏蛋  -啊
- I captured these bad boys.  - Ugh.
什么
Huh?
巴西白蚁
Brazilian termites.
非常罕见  破坏力极强而且在北美洲从未被发现
Very rare, very destructive and they've never been found in North America...
直到现在
Until now.
他们有如此强的破坏性  为什么要把它拿进咱们的房子
Well, if they're so destructive, why would you bring them into our house?
咱们木质的房子
Our wooden house?
亲爱的  我又不是白痴
Honey, I'm not an idiot.
这个容器 是有防白蚁设计的
This container... termite-proof.
-你确定吗  -十分确定
- Are you sure? - I am sure.
再者  这东西只在这里暂放一晚
Besides, it's only gonna be for one night.
明天我就把它交给丹佛大学
Tomorrow I'm taking 'em to the University of Denver.
这样他们就可以把我供奉在灭虫专家名誉堂里了
This could land me in the exterminator hall of fame.
鲍伯亲  那东西并不存在
Bob honey, that doesn't exist.
亲爱的  有的  它在底特律
Honey, yes, it does. It's in Detroit.
它曾坐落于克利夫兰  不过他们得搬走
Used to be in Cleveland, but they had to move it.
老鼠问题
Rat problem.
我知道这是一个绝佳的机会
So I know that it's a great opportunity,
但是如果斯宾塞现在就离开  我会伤心的
but if Spencer leaves now, I'm gonna be so sad.
我们本来为剩下的时光安排了好多计划
We have so many plans for the rest of the year.
等我有了男朋友  我们也会有很多计划
When I get a boyfriend, we're gonna make bunch of plans too.
或许你该计划着先找到个男朋友
Maybe you should make a plan to get a boyfriend.
或许你该计划着  别告诉我计划这个
Maybe you should make a plan not to tell me to make a plan.
排球队的朋友  哈
Volleyball friends, huh?
好  一个一个问题说
Well, one problem at a time.
斯宾塞征求我的意见
So Spencer asked me what I thought he should do...
我不知道怎么回答他
And I don't know what to tell him.
我认为既然你已经足够幸运有男朋友了的话
I think if you're lucky enough to get a boyfriend,
你永永远远也别让他离开你
you should never ever let him go...
哪怕你需要偷偷把他锁在地下室里
Even if you have to lock him in the basement and not tell anybody.
所以呢
So...
我的确不希望斯宾塞离开
Of course I don't want Spencer to go,
不过我也不希望我是那个拖他后腿的人
but I also don't want to be the one to keep him from going.
天啊  真希望我有关于这方面事情的经验
Oh man. I wish I had some experience with these things,
但不知为何男生们觉得我古怪又讨人嫌
but for some reason boys find me weird and off-putting.
不只是男生哦  亲爱的
Not just boys, sweetie.
凯西  你怎么看
Kelsey, what do you think?
我觉得不管怎样结果都会很好
I think whatever happens is gonna be great.
如果斯宾塞去的话  泰迪会崩溃的
But if Spencer goes, then Teddy will be crushed.
-有道理  -但是如果不去
- You make a good point. - And if he doesn't go,
-斯宾塞可能会难过  -你说得也有道理
- he might be miserable. - That's a good point, too.
那你到底是怎么想的呢
So what are you saying?
我觉得她俩说的都对
That I agree with everybody.
你只能赞同其中一个
But you can't agree with everybody.
说得太对了
You are absolutely right.
你又来了
You just did it again!
算了  我已经做出决定了
Okay, I've made my decision.
-啥决定  -我得交些新朋友了
- What is it? - I need some new friends.
我家小蒂蒂真的很喜欢和你家小查莉一起玩
My little Deedee just loves playing with your little Charlie.
真好
Oh.
不过呢  她上次问我  为啥查莉取了个男生的名字呢
Although, last time she asked me, "why does Charlie have a boy's name?"
（注：Charlie是男名 普遍译为查理）
我都不知道怎么回答她
And I didn't know what to tell her.
小宝贝  你和小伙伴玩得怎么样
Hey, honey. How's your play date going?
-啊  -哦
- Eh. - Mmm.
第二个问题  蒂蒂在哪呢
Follow up question: Where's Deedee?
在监狱里
In jail.
最后一个问题  她说的监狱准确来讲是什么意思
Final question: What does "jail" mean exactly?
呃  意思是  我们还是去看一下吧
Uh, well, it means, we'd better go check.
我的天哪
Oh, my.
哦  我的小蒂蒂
Oh. Oh, Deedee.
-这可不好笑  -哦  不好意思
- Not funny. - Oh, sorry.
-去吧  -嗯  你俩去玩吧
- Oh. - Yeah, you guys go play.
我们还是在这儿和姑娘们待一会儿吧
Maybe we should just stay in here with the girls for a while.
-是个好主意  -那好
- Sounds like a good idea. - Okay, sure.
至少这可以作为我博客的一个好素材
Well, at least this will make a good post for my blog.
你还写博客呢
Uh, you have a blog?
我的博客叫  黛比妈妈的生活日报
I call it "Mama Debbie's Daily Doing's".
哎呀  你说真的
Oh, you're serious.
那必须的
You betcha.
我写些食谱啊生活小窍门啊什么的
I post recipes, offer helpful hints...
分享一些和道格·杜利之间的有趣经历
Share fun things Doug Dooley and I do together.
传授母女相处之道之类的
Just passing along some of the things I've learned about motherhood and such.
哇  这么说你的博客都是基于你养这个孩子的经历了
Wow, and you've based this on your vast experience with one child?
加上即将出来的这个  一共俩
And one on the way for a total of two.
我有五个呢
Oh. I have a total of five.
这又不是什么竞赛
It's not a competition.
之前的确不是
It wasn't.
-你在这干嘛呢  -托比害得我彻夜未眠
- What are you doing down here? - Toby kept me up all night.
哈  这就叫因果报应
Ah. It's called payback.
你小时候  我也被你折腾够呛
When you were a baby, you used to make my life miserable, too.
我永远记得有一次我在你摇篮上醒来而你睡在我的床上
I will never forget the night I woke up in your crib and you were in my bed.
我到现在都不知道你是怎么做到的
I still have no idea how you did that.
让我和托比住一屋那是绝对不可能的
Well, me and Toby sharing a room is not gonna work.
我得想想办法  现在就想
Something has to be done... now.
你是要干坏事了么
Oh! Are you gonna do something bad?
那样的话就太好了
Because that'd be great...
-从我的角度来说  -你说啥呢
- For me. - What are you talking about?
因为我有个不太好的消息要告诉爸妈
Well, I have to break some difficult news to mom and dad,
估计他们知道了会生气
and they're not gonna be happy.
所以我在想如果这会儿你惹出点事
So I was thinking maybe if you got in trouble,
然后我再跟他们说  就不会把焦点放在我身上了
I could sneak my news in and kind of piggyback on your badness.
是什么事呢
Well, what's the news?
其实也没什么
Oh, it's nothing.
其实我很想帮你  但我实在是太困了
You know, I'd get it out of you, but I am way too tired.
那你是怎么想的
So what do you think?
你会很快整出点事的对么
You gonna be getting into trouble anytime soon?
不好说  这是两码事
I don't know. It's different.
我现在可是个青少年了
I'm a teenager now.
你这是什么态度
Well, what kind of attitude is that?
这次谈话还没完
That is quitter talk.
巴西白蚁
Brazilian termites.
这是自我06年发现乌克兰毛虫之后
This is the most exciting thing
最激动人心的事了
since I discovered those Ukrainian grub worms in '06.
拜托  那是我发现的
Excuse me, I discovered those.
不对  当时我在槽隙中
No, I was in the crawl space.
你在一旁看着
You were in the port-a-john.
好吧  给你
Fine. Here.
好好欣赏这些小家伙吧
Feast your eyes on those little beauties.
我看不到啊
I don't see 'em.
-不就在里面吗  -你确定么
- Well, they're in there. - Are you sure?
我只看到两个小洞
All I see are two little holes.
小洞
Holes?!
坏了
Oh no.
不不不  它们把塑料吃了
No no no! They ate right through the plastic!
出事了  出大事了
Oh, this is bad. This is really bad.
听着  咱得在白蚁繁殖之前找到它们
Okay, look, we gotta wipe 'em out before they multiply...
更重要的是  要在艾米发现之前
More importantly, before Amy finds out.
我们可以把这地方罩起来
Well, we could tent the place.
你好聪明啊
Hey, there you go.
她怎么会发现罩在屋子上的巨大的充气包呢
She'll never notice a giant gas-filled tarp covering the house.
那我们该怎么办
Well, then what are we gonna do?
我有办法了
I've got an idea.
去防虫中心
To the bug mobile!
我好喜欢他现在这个样子
I love when he does that.
宝贝  你能帮妈妈把监狱拿来不  妈妈要洗衣服了
Hey, sweetie, can you go get me the jail? Mommy needs to do laundry.
-好的  -谢谢你  宝贝
- Okay. - Thank you, sweetie.
嘿  小查莉  嘿  老妈
Hi, Charlie. Hey, mom.
-嘿  亲爱的  -您干嘛呢
- Hey, sweetie. - What you doing?
写我的妈妈博客呢
Working on my mommy blog.
妈妈博客  听上去不太像您的风格啊
Mommy blog? That doesn't sound like you.
我要完胜黛比·杜利
I am gonna kick Debbie Dooley's butt.
这才是您的风格嘛
That sounds like you.
现在唯一困扰我的是文章主题
The only problem is I'm having trouble coming up with topics.
那黛比都写些什么呢
What kind of stuff does Debbie post about?
-菜谱  -真老土
- Recipes... - Ooh, so that's out.
她还写和她老公之间的趣事  同样老土
She also writes about fun stuff she does with her husband, so that's out too.
盖比哪去了  怎么总是不见他人影
Hey, where is Gabe? He's always up to something?
但愿他能有主意
Well, here's hoping.
我是说你的博客主题
I mean for you and your blog.
没说我
Not for me.
我怎么会需要他干坏事呢
Why would I need him to do anything bad?
来了
Coming!
-嘿  -嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
-听我说  -泰迪  我
- So listen, I... - So, Teddy, I...
-你先说  -好的
- You first. - Okay, um...
那我就说了
I'm just gonna come out and say it.
我觉得你应该去波士顿
I think you should go to Boston.
其实我更倾向于不去
Because I was kinda leaning towards not going.
-为什么  -我不想离开你
- Why? - I just don't think I can leave you.
斯宾塞  但是那是你梦想的学校
Oh, Spence, but BIPA is your dream school.
有全国最好的音乐专业
It's the best musicprogram in the country
如果你不抓住这个机会
and you know if you don't grab this opportunity,
你会后悔一辈子的
you're gonna regret it for the rest of your life.
又不是只有那一所大学
Yeah, but it's not the only college out there.
我是说  我还可以申请
I mean, I could stay here and audition for
丹佛学院的表演艺术专业
the Denver Institute of Performing Arts.
-迪帕  -是的
- DIPA? - Yeah.
迪帕可比不上比帕
DIPA's not as good as BIPA.
哦是么  你知道谁上的迪帕吗
Oh yeah? You know who went to DIPA?
-凯利·瑞帕  -瑞帕上的迪帕
- Kelly Ripa. - Ripa went to DIPA?
不是  我就是想听你问这句
No, I just wanted to hear you say that.
你知道你必须要这么做
Hey, you know you have to do this.
那我们怎么办
Yeah, but what about us?
我们还是我们啊  只不过变成了异地恋而已
Well, there will still be an us, just a long-distance us.
-你真觉得那样可行  -现在通讯这么发达
- You really think we can make that work? - Hey, nothing is far away anymore.
我们可以发短信
We can... we can text.
可以打电话  视频聊天
We can talk on the phone. We can video chat.
还可以发邮件
We can email.
最大的好处在于我身上有怪味的时候
Oh, and the great part is that when I smell funny...
你也闻不到
You won't have a clue.
-你身上从来没怪味  -我知道
- Hey, you never smell funny. - I know.
没关系  亲爱的  我们能克服的
It's gonna be okay, sweetie. We can do this.
嗯  我们肯定可以的
Yeah, of course we can.
那你什么时候走
So when do you have to leave?
明天
Tomorrow.
好吧
Okay.
过来
Then come here.
明天之前  我是不会放开你了
Until tomorrow, I'm not gonna let you go.
我也是
Me neither.
外面有点冷  要进屋吗
Hey, it's kinda cold out here. You wanna go inside?
好
Sure.
来吧  饥饿的小蚂蚁们
Okay, my hungry little ants...
今日供应巴西特产
Today's special is Brazilian.
祝君好胃口
Bon Appetit.
-老爸  -嗷
- Dad? - Ow!
-PJ  -您干吗在屋里放蚂蚁啊
- P.J.! - Why are you releasing ants in the house?
呃  我是
Uh, because...
我是在训练
I'm training.
我先把蚂蚁放走然后再捕捉回来
Uh, I'm uh, letting the ants go now so I can catch 'em again later.
灭虫专家都是这么训练的
All the exterminators do it.
老爸  公平地说  我不是邓肯家最聪明的人吧
Dad, do you think it's fair to say I'm not the brightest Duncan?
相当公平  孩子
It... it's more than fair, son.
连我都不信的借口  谁会信呢
So if I'm not buying this story, who do you think will?
好吧  听着
All right, look, um...
还记得我带回家的那些巴西白蚁吗
Those Brazilian termites that I brought home?
他们跑出去了  所以我引进了一些蚂蚁
They got out, so I brought in some ants,
你知道蚂蚁以白蚁为食吧  所以很快就没事了
because the ants will eat the termites. See? So it's gonna be fine.
一切都会没事的
Everything's gonna be fine.
为什么不直接清理房子
Why don't you just tent the house?
因为我不想让你妈妈发现
Because I don't want your mom to find out.
因为妈妈发现的话情况就糟糕了
Because if mom found out, that'd be bad.
会非常糟糕的
That would be very bad.
但她是不会发现的
But she's not gonna find out.
对的  对的
Right, right.
嗯  万一她知道了  能告诉我一声么
Uh, but when she does, could you let me know?
-干什么  -就是
- Why? - Just because.
我绝对没有隐瞒什么事情不说
It's not like I have something to hide.
来了
Coming!
-有人吗  -门开着
- Hello? - It's open!
-这是什么  -我的新卧室
- What is this? - It's my new room.
才不是呢
No, it's not.
没看见我的床在这儿吗
Then what's my bed doing here?
盖比  你不能占用客厅当卧室
Gabe, you are not taking over the living room.
这又不是客厅  就是壁炉边上
It's not the living room. It's the fireplace area.
好吧  这样说我感觉好点
Oh yeah, that makes me feel better
盖比的卧室要火烧屁股了
Gabe... With fire in his room.
打包走人
Now pack it up!
这就是拉开帘子的代价
That's what I get for answering the curtain.
看见你真是太好了
It's so good to see your face.
虽然只是几天不见  但我真的好想你
I know it's only been a few days, but I miss you so much.
我也想你
I miss you too.
很抱歉我们好久没聊天了  我只是太忙了
And I'm sorry we haven't been able to talk very much it's just...
熟悉情况之类的
With orientation and everything...
没关系  我懂的
It's okay. I get it.
泰迪  帮我照看一下托比好吗
Teddy, can you give me a hand with Toby?
马上回来
Be right back.
-嘿  邓肯先生  -噢
- Hey, Mr. Duncan. - Oh!
斯宾塞  你在电脑里做什么
Spencer? What are you doing on the computer?
只是在视频聊天
Oh, just video-chatting.
嘿  最近怎么样
Hey, how about that?
你看见我挠屁股了
You see the butt scratch?
是的  先生
Yes, Sir.
有点痒
I had an itch.
没事  我能理解  但是
Oh no, I completely understand. It's just...
怎么说呢  你挠过痒后抓起了一个苹果
Well, after the scratch you picked up an apple.
然后你又放回去了
Then you put it back.
这个啊  我就是
Well, yeah, I just...
突然意识到更想吃麦片
I realized I was in the mood for cereal.
这其实不是问题所在
Not really the point.
-亲爱的我回来了  -拜拜
- Okay, I'm back.  - See you.
终于到我们的二人世界了
Finally, we're all alone.
泰迪姐姐
Hello.
查莉是例外
Except for Charlie.
-嗨  小查莉  -他怎么进到里面的
- Hi, Charlie. - How did he get in there?
小查莉  斯宾塞并不是真的在电脑里
Charlie, Spencer's not really in the computer.
他在波士顿
He's in Boston.
-你能看见我吗  - 当然
- Can you see me? - I sure can.
只是看不见你姐姐了
I just can't see your sister.
对啊  在我的新房间里颤抖呢  哥们
Yeah, just chilling in my new room, dude.
嗯  我很享受
Yeah, I'm loving it.
呃  我一会儿再给你打回去
Um, I'm gonna need to call you back.
没  只是开始甩干了而已
No, the spin cycle just started.
这可是个问题
This might be a problem.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
只是觉得我应该过来告诉你一声
Just thought I'd pop over and tell you,
-我看你的博客了  -哦
- I saw your blog. - Oh.
还有我特别喜欢你的第一篇博文  那该死的小卡莉
And I especially enjoyed your first post, "that darn Carlie".
校对是多么重要啊
So important to proofread.
噢  非常感谢
Oh. Well uh, thank you.
下次如果还有什么建设性意见的话
And next time you have any helpful suggestions,
不用特意拜访
don't come over.
对啊  就随便写在我的评论区就好
Yeah. Just feel free to put it in my comments section.
考虑的好周到
Oh, that's thoughtful.
当然  我总是乐于告诉你东西该如何安置
Mm-hmm. Well, I always enjoy telling you where to put things.
既然我来这儿了  就给你点小贴士吧
Mmm. Since I'm here now, let me give you a few tips.
我称之为  黛比·杜利的"二要二不要"
I call them "Debbie Dooley's dos and don'ts".
要使用拼写检查
Do use spell-check.
不要不使用拼写检查
Don't not use spell-check.
要记得我的博客永远都比你的出名
Do know that my blog will always be more popular than yours.
不要不这么认为
Don't think it won't.
就这样吧
Okay.
好极了  好极了
That's great. That's great.
不过  你要知道  我也有自己的友情提示
Though, you know, I have some helpful hints myself. Yeah.
要记住从哪儿来回哪儿去
Do go back to where you came from.
不要再来烦我
Don't bother me again.
你们的异地恋最近怎么样了
So how's the long-distance relationship going?
不是很好  你知道的  我们的日程安排完全不同
Not good. You know, we both have such different schedules,
甚至连聊天的时间都没有
we barely had any time to talk.
当初都告诉你该把他锁在地下室里了
Told you you should've locked him in the basement.
我知道只过了三天  但是我好想他啊
I know it's only been three days, but I miss him so much.
真想见见他
I just wish I could see him.
为什么不呢
So why don't you?
飞去波士顿  就我一个人
Fly all the way to Boston by myself?
老妈老爸不可能允许我这么做的
My mom and dad would never let me do that.
除非他们不知道
Unless they didn't know about it.
你可以跟他们说你在我家里度过周末
You could just tell them that you're spending the weekend at my house.
好主意  我喜欢
That's good. I like that.
那么这个周末  我们去
So this weekend, we'll be at...
你家
"Your house".
耶  艾薇之夜到来
<i>Yeah, sleepover at Ivy's!</i>
又不是真的
It's not really happening.
就是  又不是真的
Yeah, it's not really happening.
我会带点爆米花球来的
I'll bring the I'll bring the popcorn balls..
这感觉真好
Oh, this is nice.
-嘿  盖比  -老爸  车灯还开着
- Hey, Gabe. - You left the lights on, dad.
他们自己会灭的
They turn off by themselves.
看吧
See?
爸
Dad!
又来了  这毛病有好一阵子了
Yeah, been having some trouble with that!
好吧  睡个好觉
Well, good night!
对了  老妈  我去艾薇家过周末
Okay, mom. Well, I'm off to Ivy's for the weekend.
哇哦  你带了个相当大的箱子啊
Whoa. That's a pretty big suitcase you got there.
哦  艾薇和我打算做点扮装游戏  我们  呃
Oh, Ivy and I are doing makeovers. We're, uh... you...
你懂的  女孩游戏
You know us girls.
对了  走之前过来看看我的博客
Oh, well, before you go, come check out my blog.
噢  你有个博客
Oh, you have a blog.
-半打邓肯家族  -引人注目吧  哈
- "Half a dozen Duncans". - Catchy, huh?
艾米·邓肯历险记
"The adventures of Amy Duncan,
一个巢中挤满六只疯狂小鸟的鸟妈妈
a mama bird whose nest is bursting with six crazy chickies".
妈  你只有五个孩子啊
Mom, you only have five kids.
又编了一个
I made one up.
斯基比
Skippy.
-斯基比·邓肯  -嗯
- Skippy Duncan. - Mmm.
斯基比·玛丽·邓肯
Skippy Marie Duncan.
她今年八岁
She's eight.
老妈  你真是一位有意思的女人
You are an interesting woman, mom.
谢谢啊  亲爱的
Thank you. Thank you.
还有哦  天呐  这个斯基比可是个捣蛋鬼
And oh my goodness, this Skippy is a handful.
昨晚她因为怕黑
Last night because she was afraid of the dark,
点燃了一堆烟火
she set off a bunch of fireworks.
天呀  都引起骚动了
Boy, did that cause a ruckus.
一位非常有意思的女人
A very interesting woman.
这是怎么了
What happened?
你闯了什么祸被老爸老妈赶出来了么
Did mom and dad kick you out because you did something horrible?
拜托回答是
Please say yes.
哥们  我没闯祸  这是我的新卧室
Dude, I didn't do anything. This is my new room.
盖比  你不能住在走廊上
Gabe, you can't live on the porch.
-为什么  -嗯  比如说  这里没有灯
- Why not? - Well, for one thing, there's no light.
门廊壁灯
Porch light.
这里也没有水
There's no running water.
自来水
Hose.
那厕所呢
What about a bathroom?
这是什么
Hello.
你已经把所有的都安排好了  是吧
You've got it all figured out, huh?
你一直忙着你的新房间
Been so busy with your new room
你都忘了为你老哥去惹惹麻烦了
you forgot to get in trouble for your big brother.
到底什么事  你不敢告诉爸妈
What are you so afraid to tell mom and dad?
不能说  这太糟糕了
Can't say. It's bad.
告诉我吧  不会糟糕到哪儿去的  到底怎么了
Oh, come on, it can't be that bad. Just tell me what it is.
好的  但是你要保证不能告诉任何人
Okay, but you have to promise not to tell anybody.
我保证
I promise.
好吧  就是
All right. Here goes.
我退学了
I dropped out of college.
什么
What?!
天呐  爸妈会杀了你的
Oh man, mom and dad are gonna kill you!
你刚刚还说事情不会糟糕到哪儿去的
You just said it wasn't even that bad.
我刚刚那是不知道什么事
I didn't know what it was!
等等  你为什么要退学
Wait. Why'd you quit college?
就是因为  我并不适合大学
Because it's just... it's just not for me.
我想做一些别的事情
And there's something else I wanna do.
好吧  那你最好赶紧去做
Well, you'd better do it quick,
因为爸妈会杀了你的
because mom and dad are gonna kill you!
你已经说过一遍了
You said that already!
那你准备什么时候告诉他们
Well, when are you gonna tell 'em?
我不知道
I don't know.
应该很快吧
Soon, probably.
总有一天  老爸惹毛了老妈
There's a chance dad might be in some hot water with mom.
我就等到那时候再看怎么办
I'm gonna wait and see how that plays out.
嘿  能借你厕所一用么
Hey, can I use your bathroom?
-可以  用吧  -酷
- Yeah, sure, go ahead. - Cool.
-嘿  老婆  -嘿  亲爱的
- Oh, hey, hon.  - Hey, sweetie.
亲爱的  那儿有三明治  想吃的话自己拿
Look, babe, there's sandwich fixins over there if you're interested.
听起来
That sounds...
啊
Guh
"啊"是什么意思
"Guh"? What does that mean?
没什么
Nothing.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
就伸展一下
Just stretching.
在吃东西之前
Before you eat?
这非常重要
It's pretty important.
怎么去波士顿呢
So what's bringing you to Boston?
坐这架飞机去啊
Well, hopefully this plane.
事实上我是去看我男朋友的
No, actually, I'm gonna go visit my boyfriend.
我们是异地恋
We're in a long-distance relationship.
噢  那你遇到我就对了
Ah. Well, you're sitting next to the right guy.
以旅行为生的我  有许多许多的建议给你
I travel for a living and I've got tons of tips.
第一条  不要以旅行为生
First off, don't travel for a living.
说正经的  你需要时时都带着它
Seriously now, you're always gonna have to have one of these things handy.
看起来很舒服
Well, it looks very comfortable.
我一直都带个备用的
I always carry a spare.
谢谢
Thanks.
饿了么
Hungry?
有点  你有什么
Uh, I guess. What do you got?
华尔道夫色拉
Waldorf salad.
好吧  你只有这些么
Well, if that's all you got.
现磨黑胡椒
Fresh ground pepper?
那我就不客气了
Don't mind if I do.
对了  我叫赫伯·匹克
By the way, I'm Herb Pickier.
泰迪·邓肯  很高兴认识你
Oh, Teddy Duncan. Nice to meet you.
泰迪  你需要高压法兰盘么
Tell me, Teddy, do you have any need for high-pressure gas flanges?
呃 现在不用
Um, not at the moment.
那好吧  这是我名片
Oh. Well, take my card, anyway.
以备不时之需
You never know.
我很清楚我不需要  不过谢谢
I pretty much know, but thank you.
你准备在波士顿呆多久
So how long you gonna be in Boston?
就呆一个周末而已  我准备给我男朋友一个惊喜
Oh, just for the weekend. I'm gonna surprise my boyfriend.
我迫不及待想看到他的表情
I can't wait to see the look on his face.
我要去丹佛看我女朋友  给她一个惊喜
I'm going to Denver to surprise my girlfriend.
我迫不及待想看到她的表情
I can't wait to see the look on her face.
门开着呢
It's open.
惊喜
Surprise!
太疯狂了
This is crazy.
但我不知道你是谁
But I don't know who you are.
呃  斯宾塞在么
Ahem, um, is Spencer here?
他在丹佛  他去那儿给他女朋友惊喜
He's in Denver. He went to surprise his girlfriend.
我就是他女朋友  我是来给他惊喜的
I'm his girlfriend. I came here to surprise him.
刚刚那一会儿是挺令人激动的
Well, that was exciting for a second.
泰迪  你根本猜不到我现在在哪儿
Teddy. You're never gonna guess where I am.
-丹佛  -想不到你会这么容易猜到
- Denver? - Huh. I thought that would be harder.
那你猜猜我在哪儿
Yeah, well, guess where I am.
-波士顿  -什么
- Boston! - What?
看来我们想到一块儿去了  惊喜
Well, I guess we both had the same idea. Surprise!
天呐  太悲剧了  我们又见不到对方了
Oh gosh, this is terrible. We're not gonna be able to see each other.
不  我们会见面的  这样吧  你就呆在那儿
Yes, we are. Okay, you stay right there.
我坐最近的一趟飞机回来
I'll just take the first flight back.
好吧  可是我已经在你家门口了
Well, I mean I'm already at your front door.
我应该进去跟你爸妈打个招呼
I might as well say hi to your parents.
不要  别啊  你在干嘛呢
Don't. No no, what are you doing?
他们不知道我出来了
They don't know that I'm out here.
-可是  我刚刚按门铃了  -快点闪啊
- Well, I just rang the bell. - Just... move!
儿子  这就是传说中的"叮咚陷阱"
Son, that is what we call "ding-dong ditch".
嘿  查莉  想玩游戏么
Hey, Charlie, wanna play a game?
好的  现在我想一个数字
Okay, so I'm thinking of a number,
如果你猜到了  你就可以让托比搬过来跟你一块儿住了
and if you guess it, you get to have Toby move into your room.
想得美
Nice try.
嘿PJ  你想玩个游戏么
Hey P.J., you wanna play a game?
还在找你的新房间么
Still trying to find a bedroom, huh?
基本每个地方都试遍了
Yeah, and I've tried everywhere...
客厅  地下室  前廊
The living room, the basement, the front porch.
我猜你肯定漏了阁楼
I assume you've ruled out the attic. Ugh!
-哪里  -阁楼
- The what? - The attic. Ugh!
我们家还有阁楼
We have an attic?
对啊  在楼上
Yeah. It's upstairs.
好的  好的  我的新房间就在那儿了
Yeah yeah, that'd be the place for it.
等等  为什么我不知道我们还有阁楼
Wait. Why didn't I know we had an attic?
你还不知道我们家有一个树屋呢
You didn't know we had a tree house either.
是时候往上看看了
You gotta start looking up.
看吧  呃
See? Ugh!
不是"呃"  是"耶"
It's not "ugh!" It's..."Hey!"
-泰迪  -赫伯  嗨
- Teddy! - Herb. Hi.
嘿  在波士顿呆得怎么样了
Hey, how was your day in Boston?
不怎么样
Not so good.
给我枕头
Pillow me.
谢谢
Thanks. So...
我男朋友为了给我惊喜飞去了丹佛
My boyfriend decided to surprise me and flew out to Denver.
噢  这种陈旧的双重惊喜都会悲剧
Oh, the old double surprise gone bad.
我能为这种事唱上几首歌
I could sing a few bars of that one.
但是你不会唱的  对吧
But you're not going to, right?
不会  他们在安全通知时是不允许我这样做的
No no, they frown upon that during the safety announcement.
等到我回到丹佛的时候
It's just that by the time I get back,
我和斯宾塞也没有多少时间呆在一起
Spencer I will barely have any time together.
所有的异地恋都很残忍
All long-distance relationships are brutal.
你试着努力得去维系
You try to make 'em work.
邮件  信息  视频
You email, you text, you video chat...
突然在一个晚上你发现
Then one night you decide
你更想做的事是看"星际大战"
you'd rather watch a "Battlestar Galactica" Marathon
就这样你就当了恶人
and suddenly you're the bad guy.
我敢肯定这种事不会发生在我的身上
I'm pretty sure that won't happen to me.
从第一季就不要看  会上瘾的
Stay away from the first season. It's addictive.
我知道了
Good to know.
我想说的就是什么也不能代替
All I'm trying to say is there's no substitute
两个人在同一个地方生活
for being in the same place together,
那些认为自己是例外的人  只是自己骗自己而已
and anyone who thinks otherwise is just kidding themselves.
噢  你和你男朋友例外
Oh, except for you and your boyfriend.
你们俩会好好的
You kids'll be fine.
各位乘客  我是机长  现在通知大家
This is the Captain speaking. Just wanna let you know
现在在俄亥俄河谷上方有一股强气流
that there's some weather over the Ohio valley,
所以今晚的航班会延迟
so we're gonna be a little delayed tonight...
最多三四个小时
Three, four hours tops.
哇  好吧  这样好不好
Wha... well, here's a thought:
绕着俄亥俄飞吧
Fly around Ohio.
嗯  看样子我们要在这要多待一会儿了
Well, looks like we're gonna be here for a while.
小蛋饼
Mini quiche?
-嘿  妈妈  -嘿  PJ
- Hey, mom. - Hey, P.J.
好了  她正在那儿坐着  正好
Okay, she's sitting right there. Just...
过去把退学的事告诉她
Get it over with and tell her you dropped out of college.
如果再拖延一秒  你就
If you hold it in one more second, you'll go...
哦  有葡萄
Ooh, grapes!
啥时候买的
When did we get those?
妈妈一定去超市了
Mom must've gone to the store.
但她老是不洗葡萄啊
But she doesn't always wash them.
我是不是吃了个没洗的葡萄
Did I just eat an unwashed grape?
我来厨房做什么来着
What am I doing in the kitchen?
哦  对了
Oh, right.
妈妈
Mom?
有件事要告诉你
There's something I gotta tell ya.
喂
Hello.
是的  等一下
Yeah, hold on.
有个"早安丹佛"的人找你
Uh, somebody from "Good Morning, Denver" wants to talk to you.
"早安丹佛"  那个电视秀
"Good Morning, Denver"? The TV show?
是啊
Yeah.
我想我可以给他一分钟时间
I think I have a minute.
你好
Hello.
我就是
This is she.
嗯啊
Uh-huh.
我想我可以安排一下
I... I think I could arrange something.
哦  太好了
Oh, very good.
好的  谢谢你的来电
Yes, thank you for calling.
怎么了
What's going on?
老娘要上电视了
I'm gonna be on TV!
哇  太好了  妈妈
Wow, that's great, mom.
他们喜欢我的妈咪博客  还给我安排了一次电视访谈
They loved my mommy blog and they want me to do a segment on the show!
要是一切顺利的话  我就能成常驻了
And if it all goes well, be a regular.
-他们这么说的  -没  他们一定会的
- They said that? - No, but they will!
等着我上了电视吧
After I'm on TV.
这是所有的白蚁笼子了
Well, I think that's all the ant traps.
好了  现在捕蚁任务完成
Okay. Well, by now the ants have done their job
-白蚁都没了  -但愿如此
- and the termites are gone. - Sure hope so.
得了吧  收拾得了两千个蚂蚁弄不好两个白蚁
Come on, 2,000 ants against two termites?
我愿意赌一下
I think I likes me my odds.
哦不  白蚁
Oh no, I... it's termites!
好多
Dozens of 'em!
它们怎么能繁殖的这么快
How did they multiply so fast?
嗯  它们在邓肯家
Well, they are in the Duncan house.
也算是入乡随俗吧
Kind of a "when in Rome" situation?
我们得隔离房子了
Ah. We're gonna have to tent the house.
我怎么跟艾米说啊
What am I gonna tell Amy?
可以跟她实话实说
You could tell her the truth.
或者是
Or...
-度假  -是的
- A vacation? - Yes.
亲爱的  你这么辛苦
Honey, you work so hard,
忙前忙后的  你值得拥有一次度假
you do so much around here you deserve a vacation.
好吧  好主意  你计划啥时候开始
Well, okay. That sounds great. When were you thinking?
从周二早八点到周四早八点
8:00 A.M. Tuesday to 8:00 A.M. Thursday.
48小时的欢乐时光
48 hours of fun!
就带上你  我  孩子们还有过期的食物
Just you, me, the kids and the perishables.
鲍伯  这可不行
Bob, Bob, I can't do that.
周二早晨我得上电视  记得不
I'm gonna be on TV Tuesday morning, remember?
哦  是啊  嗯
Oh, right. Um...
好吧  没问题  你完事了我们再走
Okay, no problem. We'll leave right after you're done.
好吧  主意不错
Okay, sounds great.
嘿  我们为什么要带上过期的食物
Hey, why are we taking the perishables?
因为
Because...
我们
We...
来了
Coming!
-终于  -哦 我的宝贝
- Finally. - Oh there's my girl.
嘿  昨晚啥时候到的
Hey, what time did you get in last night?
凌晨4点  我太抱歉了
4:00 A.M. I am so sorry.
飞机延迟  蛋饼凉了
The plane got delayed, quiches went cold,
赫伯只带了一份沙拉
Herb only brought one side salad...
整个一场悲剧啊
It was a complete disaster.
赫伯
Herb?
是的  你往回飞的话也许能碰上他
Yeah, you'll probably meet him on the flight back.
但重要的是现在我们终于在一起了
But the important thing is that we're together now.
嗯嗯  只有一个小时
Well, for an hour.
什么
What?
是的  我必须要赶飞机  明天有课
Yeah, I have to catch a plane. I've got class tomorrow.
嗯  太棒了  那我得等到春假才能再见到你
Well, great. So I have to wait until spring break to see you again?
哦 天啊
Oh. Gosh.
我父母春假来波士顿
My parents are coming to Boston for spring break.
所以  我们接下来五个月只有这一小时在一起
So we have one hour together in five months?
嗯嗯  我们可以找几个周末找对方
Well, we can find a couple ofweekends to visit each other.
不  斯宾塞  我做不到
No, Spence, I can't.
我爸妈都不知道我去你那了
My parents don't even know that I took this trip,
我不能再向他们说谎
I can't lie to them again.
那我们该怎么办
Well, what are we gonna do?
我不知道  我不知道这会这么难
I don't know. I didn't know it was gonna be this hard.
是啊  我也是
Yeah, me neither.
我不能把我所有的时间都花在想你上
I just can't spend all my time missing you.
我会疯掉的
I'm gonna drive myself crazy.
是的  我也这么觉得
Yeah, I feel the same way.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
嗯  我是说  我们什么都做不了  除了
Well, I mean, there's nothing we can do, except...
我不想说出来
I don't wanna say it.
是的  我也不想说
Yeah, I don't wanna say it either.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
Oh, I love you too.
我会想死你的
I'm gonna miss you so much.
你俩为啥这么悲伤
Why you so sad?
因为我们在说再见  查莉  并且
Well because we're saying goodbye, Charlie, and...
这很难说出口
It's a very hard thing to do.
那就说  你好
Then say, "hello".
是啊
Yeah.
是啊  也许那会轻松一些
Yeah, maybe that's easier.
你好  泰迪
Hello, Teddy.
你好  斯宾塞
Hello, Spencer.
偶甜美滴家
Home sweet home.
哦  盖比里埃尔·邓肯  这发生什么事了
Oh! Gabriel Duncan, what is going on?
这是我的新房间
This is my new room.
你咋知道这个阁楼的呢
I didn't think you knew about the attic.
嗯  空穴来风
Well, the word gets around.
花了13年  才打探到这个情报的
It took 13 years, but it got around.
亲爱的  你不能把阁楼变成你的卧室
Honey, you cannot turn the attic into your bedroom.
你不能  也许我能
You can't, but maybe I can.
啥
What?
我正找些话题好在电视上讲
Well, I've been looking for something to talk about on TV tomorrow,
这点子太棒了
and this is perfect!
我家不够大  但我灵思妙想了一下
My house was too small, but I had a brainstorm.
你灵思妙想了一下
You had a brainstorm?
肯定不是斯基比想的啊
Well, it sure wasn't Skippy.
不不不
No no no.
嗨  泰迪  还记得我不
Hi, Teddy, remember me?
没心情  PJ
Not now, P.J.
哦  我可不认识什么PJ
Oh, I don't know any P.J.
我是袜袜偶人  袜袜
I'm Socky the sock puppet.
是啊  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
当你小时候伤心时  我经常让你开心起来
When you were little and feeling sad, I used to cheer you up.
这就是我现在要做的
And that's what I'm here to do now.
让我们把那个下弯的眉毛翘起来
Let's turn that frown upside down!
我真够呛
I don't think I can.
袜袜  还是交给我吧
Better let me handle this, Socky.
好的
Okay.
我知道这很难受  但相信我  这是最艰难的时候
I know it hurts, but trust me, this is the hardest part.
我就是太想他了
I just miss him so much.
会好起来的  会好起来的
It's gonna get better. It's gonna get better.
我了解  因为我也经历过这些
I know because I've been through this.
记得当斯凯勒离开时  我以为我的世界完蛋了
Remember when Skyler moved away? I thought my world was over
但我还是设法挺过来了
but,somehow I managed to move on.
你也会的
You will too.
嗯  我只是
Well, I just...
我不想结束这段感情
I don't want it to be over.
或许并不会结束
Maybe it isn't.
你的意思是
What do you mean?
或许以后  等机缘合适时
Maybe someday, when the timing's right...
你和斯宾塞会还会在一起的
You and Spence will be together again.
噢哦  棉线球
Uh-oh, lint ball.
嘿  这样才对嘛
Hey, there it is.
终于看到笑容了
There's that smile.
噢  袜袜
Oh, Socky.
什么时候我老哥变得这么聪明了
When did my big brother get to be so wise?
-从他退学后  -你干什么了
- When he dropped out of college.  - You did what?!
我不知道他在胡说些什么
I don't know what he's talking about.
感觉紧张吗宝贝
How you feeling, sweetie?
你准备好了没
You doing okay?
我感觉好极了  妈妈
I'm good, mommy.
哦  亲爱的  我在问泰迪呢
Oh, honey, I was talking to Teddy.
不紧张  我很放松  妈妈
No, I'm okay, mom.
不用担心我了
But don't worry about me.
今天是你的大日子
Today is your big day.
嘿  妈妈要上电视了
Hey, mommy's gonna be on TV.
太棒了  太棒了
Yeah yeah.
泰迪  听着  如果你想倾诉
Teddy, look, if you ever need to talk.
-随时可以找我  -谢谢
- You know I'm here for you.  - Thanks.
快说  跟她坦白
Go ahead, tell her.
把谎称去别人家过夜而跑到波士顿的事跟她坦白
Tell her you lied about the sleepover and went to Boston.
现在是绝佳时机啊
Now's the perfect time.
她心情大好而且
She's in a good mood and...
噢  有葡萄
Ooh! Grapes.
不错  不错  感觉好多了
Yes yes, much better.
感觉实在是好很多  早就想把这扇门给拆了
Much better. Been wanting to get rid of that door for years.
这下感觉空间敞亮多了
It really opens the space up.
鲍伯  到底怎么回事  为什么房子里的东西一直断裂
Bob, what is going on? Why do things keep breaking?
亲爱的  东西断裂呢
Honey, things break.
是时有发生的  你真正该问的是
Happens all the time. The real question...
为什么以前家里的东西老不断裂
Is "why weren't things breaking before?"
谢谢  菲尔  让我们来首度采访
Thanks, Phil. And now let's say hello
多子妈妈博客的博主艾米·邓肯
to mommy blogger Amy Duncan.
-早上好  艾米  -早上好  简
- Good morning, Amy.  - Good morning, Jan.
早上好  丹佛
And Good Morning, Denver.
今天你打算跟大家分享点什么呢  艾米
So what are you going to talk to us about today, Amy?
分享解决问题之道  简
Problem-solving, Jan.
当你家和我这个多子妈妈的家一样拥挤不堪的时候
When your nest is as full as this mama bird's,
你也会想尽办法去腾出更多的空间
you're always finding ways to make more room.
我所有忠实的粉丝都知道我的小女儿查莉
All of my loyal readers know that my youngest daughter Charlie,
和她姐姐斯基比同住一间房
shares a room with her sister Skippy.
-谁  -嘘
- Who?  - Shh!
斯基比很调皮捣蛋  是吧
And that Skippy is quite a handful, isn't she?
那是  这要讲起来就一发难收  简
Oh, don't get me started, Jan.
不管怎样
Anyway...
如今  我的宝宝托比得需要个单独的房间
Now that baby Toby needs his own room,
我必须找个地方安置我那已经长成小伙子的儿子盖比
I have to find someplace to put my teenage boy, Gabe.
说真的  我们真是想尽了办法
And believe me, we tried everywhere...
从卧室到地下室甚至是前廊都考虑过
The living room, the basement, even the front porch.
最后我突然想到
And then it hit me...
为什么不把阁楼清理出来把它布置成个舒适的阁楼顶房呢
Why not clear out the attic and convert it into a really cool loft space?
想到这儿后  我说干就干
Well, that's exactly what I did.
清理阁楼不是件容易事  但如我所常说
It was a lot of hard work, but as I always say,
一个多子妈妈的首要任务就是筑好爱巢
a mama bird's job is to build the perfect nest.
把麦拿一下行吗  简
Could you hold this, Jan?
我们还是去演播室接着录节目吧  简
Let's kick it back to the studio, Jan.
不  不  不  我觉得继续在这儿录比较好
No no no, I think we'll keep it right here.
艾米  能解释一下刚才是怎么回事吗
What just happened, Amy?
问得好  鲍伯
Good question. Bob?
好吧
Um, okay.
呃  记得我前几天带回家的白蚁吗
Uh, you know those termites I brought home the other day?
它们从容器中逃出了
They kinda got out.
你让白蚁蛀食我们的房子
You let termites eat our house?
-我从大学辍学了  -什么
- I dropped out of college.  - What?!
我没经你允许就去了波士顿
And I went to Boston without your permission.
-什么  -哇噢
- What?!  - Wow!
多子妈妈  看来你的爱巢正在塌裂
Mama bird, it looks like your nest is falling apart...
而且是分崩离析  有什么想说的吗
In more ways than one. What do you have to say?
事情都搅得一团糟了
This whole thing is a disaster.
或许我也可以把斯基比是瞎编的告诉她
Might as well tell her that Skippy's a lie too.
说啊  尽管说
Just go ahead. Just do it.
现在转入天气预报时段
And now for the weather.
天空是如此的
The skies are...
阳光普照  晴空万里
Sunny and clear.
交给你了  菲尔
Back to you, Phil.
好了  伙计们  快
Okay, you guys, come on.
快点  我们走吧  赶紧行动
Come on, let's go. Shake a leg.
我好不容易有了自己的房间又要搬走了
I finally get my own room and now we have to move out.
只是出去暂住几晚上而已
It's just for a couple of nights.
我们要全面检查房子  确保房子各处安全
We're gonna get the house checked out, make sure everything's safe...
还有除掉白蚁
Take care of the termite problem.
我认为那已经包含在内了
I thought that was implied.
做完那些我们就可以搬回来
And then we are gonna move back in
一切也就恢复正常了
and everything's gonna be back to normal.
你口中的"正常"是指
What do you mean, "normal"?
-PJ都从大学辍学了  -泰迪还偷偷去波士顿了
- P.J. dropped out of college.  - Teddy went to Boston.
-老爸把白蚁带进家里  -那  盖比
- Dad brought termites in the house.  - Well, Gabe...
-你犯什么错来着  -没犯错
- What did you do?  - Nothing.
像往常一样  我是好孩子
As usual, I'm the good one.
鲍伯  整个家都乱的不成样了
Bob, this family is completely falling apart.
不是这样的
No, it isn't.
听着  老爸老妈  我离开大学有我的原因
Look, guys, I dropped out of college for a reason.
我想上烹饪学校
I want to go to culinary school.
我擅长烹饪  我热爱那一行而且我戴上厨师帽很帅
I'm good at cooking, I'm passionate about it and I look good in the hat.
好吧  看到你对未来有点规划让我现在感觉好点
Okay, well, I feel better now that you have a plan.
好吧  但说到你  小姐  你被关禁闭了
Yeah, well, as for you, young lady, you are grounded.
接下来你得在你房间待很长时间
You're gonna be spending a lotta time in your room.
可我没有房间啊
I don't have a room.
呃  我跟你爸会给你弄间房然后让你老实待在里面
Well, we're gonna find you a room and I'm gonna put you in it.
好了  快点  伙计们  走吧
All right. Come on, guys, let's go.
-你能  -嗯
- Can you...  - Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了  我的爱房  过几天再见吧
Okay, house, see you in a couple of days.
或许不止几天
Or longer.
嗨  查莉  我回来了  呃  刚说到哪了
Hi, Charlie, I'm back. Um, where was I?
对  最倒霉的一天
Oh, right... worst day ever.
因为整个房子都被白蚁蛀食  所以我们无处可居
So the whole house was eaten by termites and we don't have a place to live.
呃  是的  这太糟糕了
Ugh. Yeah, it's a disaster.
对你来说不是  你有你自己的公寓
Well, not for you. You have your own apartment.
说的是  这样一说我感觉好多了
Oh yeah. That makes me feel better.
再见
See ya.
其他人就没那么好运了
Well, the rest of us have no idea
我们将寄身何处呢  但我确信我们一定会挺过去
where we'll end up, but I'm sure we'll be fine.
但以防万一  祝我们好运吧  查莉
But just in case, wish us good luck, Charlie.
-他去比帕参观了  -哪儿
- He was visiting BIPA.  - Whapa?
比帕就是波士顿教育
BIPA, the bostotin...
波士顿教育  不好意思
Bostotin... sorry.
算了  我去看下那词  看下  看下
Okay, I'm good, I'm good, I'm good.
-哪儿  -比帕就是波士顿教育
- Whapa?  - BIPA, the bostonin...
比帕就是波士顿教育学院
BIPA, the Boston instit...
哪儿
Whapa?
拍摄进展得如此顺利
It's all going so well.
嘿  甜心
Hey, sweetie.
哦  桌上有三明治小说如果
Oh, there's some sandwich fictions if...
-我不会念那个词  -倒回场景重拍
- I can't say that word.  - Go back to one.
我是南方人  我应该会说"fixins"这个词的
I'm from the South. I should be able to say "fixins".
好吧  还有个问题  灯光问题怎么解决
Well, for one thing, there's no light.
用走廊的灯
Porch light.
指错地方了
No.
-走廊的灯在这儿  -在那边呢
- Porch light's right here.  - It's right there.
异地恋进展的怎么样
So how's the long-distance relationship going?
不是太
Not go...
外面似乎  有飞车党路过这里吗
There's, like, a motorcycle gang going by the set right now.
我不知道啊  我只是觉得有点突然
I don't know I'm just kinda in shock.
嗯  我也是
Yeah, me too.
有没有人想吃芬香飘溢的新英格兰杂脍鸡肉面
Who's ready for some delicious New England chicken noodle chowder?
肩挑面包
Shoulder bread?